{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Fate smiles ...... those who untiringly grapple with stark realities of life.", "opta": "with", "optb": "over", "optc": "on", "optd": "round", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The miser gazed ...... at the pile of gold coins in front of him.", "opta": "avidly", "optb": "admiringly", "optc": "thoughtfully", "optd": "earnestly", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Catching the earlier train will give us the ...... to do some shopping.", "opta": "chance", "optb": "luck", "optc": "possibility", "optd": "occasion", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I saw a ...... of cows in the field.", "opta": "group", "optb": "herd", "optc": "swarm", "optd": "flock", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The grapes are now ...... enough to be picked.", "opta": "ready", "optb": "mature", "optc": "ripe", "optd": "advanced", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Success in this examination depends ...... hard work alone.", "opta": "at", "optb": "over", "optc": "for", "optd": "on", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "My uncle decided to take ...... and my sister to the market.", "opta": "I", "optb": "mine", "optc": "me", "optd": "myself", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you smuggle goods into the country, they may be ...... by the customs authority.", "opta": "possessed", "optb": "punished", "optc": "confiscated", "optd": "fined", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Man does not live by ...... alone.", "opta": "food", "optb": "bread", "optc": "meals", "optd": "diet", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Piyush behaves strangely at times and, therefore, nobody gets ...... with him.", "opta": "about", "optb": "through", "optc": "along", "optd": "up", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rohan and Rohit are twin brothers, but they do not look ......", "opta": "unique", "optb": "different", "optc": "likely", "optd": "alike", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To err is ...... to forgive divine.", "opta": "beastly", "optb": "human", "optc": "inhuman", "optd": "natural", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ruling party will have to put its own house ...... order.", "opta": "in", "optb": "on", "optc": "to", "optd": "into", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "...... of old paintings is a job for experts.", "opta": "Resurrection", "optb": "Retrieval", "optc": "Restoration", "optd": "Resumption", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During Diwali the shops are ...... of people.", "opta": "busy", "optb": "full", "optc": "crowded", "optd": "bubbling", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The paths of glory lead ...... to the grave.", "opta": "straight", "optb": "but", "optc": "in", "optd": "directly", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The telephone ...... several times before I answered it.", "opta": "was ringing", "optb": "has rung", "optc": "had rung", "optd": "would ring", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He passed the examination in the first class because he ......", "opta": "was hard working for it", "optb": "worked hardly for it", "optc": "had worked hard for it", "optd": "was working hard for it", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Jawaharlal spent his childhood ...... Anand Bhawan.", "opta": "at", "optb": "in", "optc": "on", "optd": "across", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If negotiations are to prove fruitful, there must not only be sincerity on each side, but there must also be ...... in the sincerity of the other side.", "opta": "faith", "optb": "belief", "optc": "substance", "optd": "certainty", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I hate sitting ...... him as he always smells of garlic.", "opta": "besides", "optb": "along", "optc": "at", "optd": "beside", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Some regions of our country still remain ...... to the average man.", "opta": "inaccessible", "optb": "impossible", "optc": "impermeable", "optd": "impenetrable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It ...... that Prashant will not be selected for the post", "opta": "feels", "optb": "looks", "optc": "believes", "optd": "seems", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In Bush, Saddam was up ...... more than his match.", "opta": "for", "optb": "into", "optc": "against", "optd": "to", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I haven't seen you ...... a week.", "opta": "within", "optb": "since", "optc": "for", "optd": "from", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I listened, but I had no idea what he was ...... about.", "opta": "saying", "optb": "talking", "optc": "telling", "optd": "discussing", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The car in which the minister was traveling ...... with an accident.", "opta": "hit", "optb": "drove", "optc": "crashed", "optd": "met", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The non cooperative attitude of the members can only ...... the image of the society.", "opta": "spoil", "optb": "improve", "optc": "degrade", "optd": "defame", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sonika is quite intelligent but rather ......", "opta": "idealistic", "optb": "generous", "optc": "lazy", "optd": "optimistic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a little-publicised deal, Pepsi, Cola has ...... the entire soft drink market in Afghanistan.", "opta": "occupied", "optb": "conquered", "optc": "swallowed", "optd": "captured", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He ...... in wearing the old fashioned coat in spite of his wife's disapproval.", "opta": "insists", "optb": "persists", "optc": "desists", "optd": "resists", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "She ...... a brief appearance at the end of party.", "opta": "put on", "optb": "put in", "optc": "put across", "optd": "put up", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Life is to death as pleasure is to ......", "opta": "poverty", "optb": "suffering", "optc": "anguish", "optd": "pain", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This, partly, explains how the Mehta family has been able to ...... its lavish lifestyle in recent times, despite the fact that all its assets have been ......", "opta": "keep, removed", "optb": "afford, attached", "optc": "develop, liquidated", "optd": "keep up, destroyed", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The machine is difficult to build ...... easy to maintain.", "opta": "but", "optb": "and", "optc": "for", "optd": "if", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you work beyond your capacity, you will naturally feel ......", "opta": "drowsy", "optb": "tired", "optc": "confident", "optd": "giddy", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you persists in telling lies to me I shall sue you ...... slander.", "opta": "to", "optb": "on", "optc": "for", "optd": "with", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "His father-in-law ...... him up in business.", "opta": "put", "optb": "made", "optc": "set", "optd": "built", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "...... works of reference are valuable as Encyclopedia, Brittanica.", "opta": "A few", "optb": "Few", "optc": "The few", "optd": "Fewer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This book is quite similar ......", "opta": "with the \"Treasure Island\"", "optb": "of that film we saw at school", "optc": "to the one I read last week", "optd": "than a story told by our teacher", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If our friends are not able to take us in their car, we must make ...... arrangements to go to the airport.", "opta": "alternative", "optb": "another", "optc": "alternate", "optd": "possible", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A crescendo of metallic thuds arose from the market, where the iron-smiths were ...... the pieces of metals.", "opta": "flattening", "optb": "striking", "optc": "hammering", "optd": "thrashing", "ans": "C", "explanation": "We use the word 'hammering' when we would like to say about the events related to \nmetals."}, {"question": "I haven't eaten an apple ...... a long while.", "opta": "from", "optb": "since", "optc": "for", "optd": "until", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The parliament invested the new organisation ...... judicial authority.", "opta": "by", "optb": "with", "optc": "from", "optd": "through", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Owing to the power cut in the area, factories are being forced to ...... men", "opta": "throw away", "optb": "send off", "optc": "put off", "optd": "lay off", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Man must ...... to stop pollution.", "opta": "act", "optb": "perform", "optc": "operate", "optd": "behave", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He was sent to the prison for his ......", "opta": "sin", "optb": "vice", "optc": "crime", "optd": "guilt", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The answer was written ...... blue ink.", "opta": "with", "optb": "by", "optc": "in", "optd": "on", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Many ...... decisions were taken at the meeting.", "opta": "hectic", "optb": "historic", "optc": "historical", "optd": "histrionic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Those who persist in the endeavor at long last triumph ...... the odds of life.", "opta": "over", "optb": "on", "optc": "upon", "optd": "about", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the modern materialistic society, the only aim of people appears to be ...... money by fair means or foul.", "opta": "print", "optb": "produce", "optc": "acquire", "optd": "extort", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the ...... for an air letter?", "opta": "fare", "optb": "value", "optc": "postage", "optd": "stamp", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He became enamored ...... her grace when he first saw her dance.", "opta": "with", "optb": "of", "optc": "by", "optd": "in", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rama was so badly injured that he needed ...... care in the hospital.", "opta": "extensive", "optb": "little", "optc": "deep", "optd": "intensive", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You cannot devise a method which ...... all possibility of errors.", "opta": "excludes", "optb": "includes", "optc": "avoids", "optd": "ignores", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Many areas of the city were ...... into darkness for several hours.", "opta": "spread", "optb": "plunged", "optc": "merged", "optd": "deep", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Find the ...... that accompany these cartoons.", "opta": "topics", "optb": "titles", "optc": "captions", "optd": "headings", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I don't really know how to ...... the problem.", "opta": "tackle", "optb": "cope", "optc": "draw", "optd": "erase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The English schemed to continue their rule in India by playing off one community ...... the other.", "opta": "before", "optb": "upon", "optc": "against", "optd": "with", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The passengers were afraid, but the captain ...... them that there was no danger.", "opta": "promised", "optb": "assured", "optc": "advised", "optd": "counselled", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The family gave father a gold watch on the ...... of his fiftieth birthday.", "opta": "time", "optb": "event", "optc": "occasion", "optd": "celebration", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The park ...... as far as the river.", "opta": "extends", "optb": "advances", "optc": "enlarges", "optd": "emerges", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Many of the advances of civilisation have been conceived by young people just on the ...... of adulthood", "opta": "boundary", "optb": "threshold", "optc": "peak", "optd": "horizon", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Arti pulled a long ...... when she was told that she could not go to Agra.", "opta": "mouth", "optb": "skirt", "optc": "face", "optd": "hand", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Brothers must live in harmony. They must never fall ......", "opta": "off", "optb": "out", "optc": "apart", "optd": "away", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I was astounded at his ...... lack of knowledge about the Continent of Africa.", "opta": "abundant", "optb": "colossal", "optc": "huge", "optd": "great", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ayesha always ...... the permission of her father before going for movies.", "opta": "seeking", "optb": "seeks", "optc": "sought", "optd": "seeker", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He felt no ...... as he plunged the knife into her back.", "opta": "qualms", "optb": "scruple", "optc": "conscience", "optd": "morals", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You haven't had your lunch yet, ...... you?", "opta": "are", "optb": "aren't", "optc": "have", "optd": "haven't", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The manner in which bombs exploded in five trains with in a short span of time suggests that it is a part of a ......", "opta": "game", "optb": "conspiracy", "optc": "villainy", "optd": "sabotage", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wheat ...... carbohydrates, vitamins, proteins, and dietary fibre in our daily diet.", "opta": "has", "optb": "gives", "optc": "yields", "optd": "provides", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The waiter hasn't brought the coffee ...... I've been here an hour already.", "opta": "till", "optb": "up", "optc": "yet", "optd": "still", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In our zeal for progress we should not ...... executive with more power.", "opta": "avoid", "optb": "give", "optc": "enhance", "optd": "arm", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You've only three months to complete the course, Don't give ...... now.", "opta": "out", "optb": "away", "optc": "up", "optd": "off", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The traveler slept under the ...... shade of banyan tree.", "opta": "cold", "optb": "cool", "optc": "cooling", "optd": "dark", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "She has an aversion ...... taking even onion and garlic.", "opta": "with", "optb": "at", "optc": "against", "optd": "to", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The river overflowed its ...... and flooded the area.", "opta": "edges", "optb": "fronts", "optc": "limits", "optd": "banks", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "...... The arrival of the police, nobody went near the victim.", "opta": "Unless", "optb": "Although", "optc": "Even", "optd": "Till", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When I was a child, I ......to school everyday instead going by cycle.", "opta": "had walked", "optb": "walked", "optc": "have walked", "optd": "have been walking", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Farida sings very well and ...... does salim.", "opta": "even", "optb": "too", "optc": "also", "optd": "so", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The old Nature versus ...... debate regarding crime continues even today.", "opta": "Man", "optb": "Universe", "optc": "Culture", "optd": "Nurture", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Sun ...... at six this morning.", "opta": "raised", "optb": "rose", "optc": "arose", "optd": "aroused", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "That rule is applicable ...... every one.", "opta": "to", "optb": "for", "optc": "about", "optd": "with", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Her parents will never give their ...... to so much an unsuitable match.", "opta": "acquiescence", "optb": "consent", "optc": "agreement", "optd": "willingness", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He tried to ...... himself against a horde of ruffians.", "opta": "collect", "optb": "save", "optc": "support", "optd": "defend", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to corporate circles data is pushing through the merger to create financially ...... company in the processed foods business, the group's thrust area for the 1990's", "opta": "acceptable", "optb": "powerful", "optc": "leading", "optd": "straight", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Indeed, all over the world, more and more people are ...... coffee.", "opta": "wanting", "optb": "drinking", "optc": "liking", "optd": "partaking", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Like any other country India has its ...... share of superstitions.", "opta": "proper", "optb": "abundant", "optc": "fair", "optd": "peculiar", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The new education policy provides a useful ...... for the planners to remove illiteracy.", "opta": "breakup", "optb": "breakthrough", "optc": "breakaway", "optd": "break-in", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "People who ...... on horses usually lose in the end.", "opta": "gamble", "optb": "play", "optc": "risk", "optd": "place", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "About twenty clerks were made ...... when the banks introduced computers.", "opta": "dispensable", "optb": "redundant", "optc": "expandable", "optd": "obsolete", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After the rain the weather ...... and the sun came out.", "opta": "cleared out", "optb": "cleared up", "optc": "cleared away", "optd": "cleared off", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The building comprises ...... sixty rooms.", "opta": "of", "optb": "onto", "optc": "by", "optd": "no preposition needed", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Namrata was found to ...... the required qualifications for the job.", "opta": "contain", "optb": "disclose", "optc": "posses", "optd": "acquire", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Government buildings are ...... on the Republic day.", "opta": "enlightened", "optb": "lightened", "optc": "illuminated", "optd": "glowed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "we had ...... wonderful time at the party last night.", "opta": "such a", "optb": "so", "optc": "such", "optd": "very", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An employment advertisement should ...... the number of vacancies.", "opta": "provide", "optb": "specify", "optc": "contain", "optd": "declare", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When varun left the cocktail party he was as ...... as a judge.", "opta": "sober", "optb": "drunk", "optc": "brave", "optd": "wise", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The criminal seems to have acted in ...... the three others.", "opta": "collusion", "optb": "coalition", "optc": "collision", "optd": "cohesion", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Soft minded individuals are ...... to embrace all kinds superstitions.", "opta": "disposed", "optb": "eager", "optc": "reluctant", "optd": "prone", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The stenographer is very efficient. He is ...... to his firm.", "opta": "a boon", "optb": "a credit", "optc": "a blessing", "optd": "an asset", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "However, the group's long-term strategy is to ...... on core sector business connected with infrastructure and energy.", "opta": "breed", "optb": "develop", "optc": "concentrate", "optd": "depend", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The man came in a van to ...... the television set.", "opta": "mend", "optb": "reform", "optc": "correct", "optd": "alter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nobody can ...... me to do anything which I do not want to do.", "opta": "encourage", "optb": "request", "optc": "oppose", "optd": "compel", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sanguine outlook is associated with the ......", "opta": "rationalist", "optb": "socialist", "optc": "philanthropist", "optd": "optimist", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "His conduct is bad, and his honesty is not ...... suspicion.", "opta": "above", "optb": "beyond", "optc": "under", "optd": "in", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is 14 years since i ...... him.", "opta": "have seen", "optb": "had seen", "optc": "saw", "optd": "see", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It being an ...... issue, it is not correct to introduce questions of morality in to the debate.", "opta": "moral", "optb": "immoral", "optc": "amoral", "optd": "irrelevant", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Natwarlal ...... them all for a ride by producing false documents.", "opta": "took", "optb": "cheated", "optc": "kept", "optd": "let", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "True brevity ...... in saying only what needs to be said.", "opta": "consists", "optb": "depicts", "optc": "portrays", "optd": "resides", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Health is too important to be ......", "opta": "discarded", "optb": "despised", "optc": "detested", "optd": "neglected", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In hot weather I like lying in the ...... of a tree.", "opta": "shade", "optb": "shelter", "optc": "protection", "optd": "shadow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It was indeed unreasonable ...... him to leave this job and start business.", "opta": "in", "optb": "with", "optc": "upon", "optd": "of", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One major ...... between the Election Commission and the Union Government related to the powers of the former in respect of the deployment of central police forces at places where are elections is held.", "opta": "irritant", "optb": "conflict", "optc": "pain", "optd": "culprit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We shall not to be able to use your ability in court unless we can find someone to ...... to statements.", "opta": "corroborate", "optb": "avouch", "optc": "verify", "optd": "approve", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is too dull ...... this problem.", "opta": "solving", "optb": "to solving", "optc": "to solve", "optd": "solves", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is the person who is ...... to blame.", "opta": "mostly", "optb": "sure", "optc": "most", "optd": "bound", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We had to pay more taxi fare because the driver brought us by a ...... route.", "opta": "circular", "optb": "circumscribed", "optc": "longest", "optd": "circuitous", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He was accused ...... stealing his aunt's necklace.", "opta": "for", "optb": "with", "optc": "of", "optd": "on", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He knew everything better than anybody else, and it was an affront to his ...... vanity that you should disagree with him.", "opta": "overstrung", "optb": "overweening", "optc": "overwhelming", "optd": "overwrought", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It's very kind of you to ...... to speak at the meeting.", "opta": "accept", "optb": "agree", "optc": "comply", "optd": "concur", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pakistan lost a ...... wicket just when they seemed to be doing so well, and that led to their eventual defeat.", "opta": "critical", "optb": "crucial", "optc": "sensitive", "optd": "providential", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sita's heart ...... at the sight of the beautiful diamond necklace.", "opta": "leapt", "optb": "stopped", "optc": "slowed", "optd": "ran", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He lives near a lovely ...... of countryside.", "opta": "length", "optb": "piece", "optc": "section", "optd": "stretch", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ambition is one of those ......which are never satisfied.", "opta": "ideas", "optb": "fancies", "optc": "passions", "optd": "feeds", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is a person of sound character and ...... disposition.", "opta": "beneficent", "optb": "morous", "optc": "amiable", "optd": "amicable", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If I take a state roadways bus, I'll get late, ...... ?", "opta": "isn't it", "optb": "won't I", "optc": "will I", "optd": "is it", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In high school many of us never realised  the importance that grammar would ...... in later life.", "opta": "figure", "optb": "portray", "optc": "play", "optd": "exercise", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a changing and ...... unstructured business environment, creativity and innovation are being ...... demanded of executives.", "opta": "highly, extremely", "optb": "progressively, increasingly", "optc": "increasingly, moderately", "optd": "excessively, rapidly", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On account of the dearth of grass on the arid plains the cattle became ......", "opta": "flippant", "optb": "jubilant", "optc": "agitated", "optd": "emaciated", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A woman came in with a baby who, she said, ...... a safety pin.", "opta": "was just swallowing", "optb": "swallowed", "optc": "had just swallowed", "optd": "just swallowed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Hubble Space Telescope will search for planets around the stars, a key to the ...... extraterrestrial life, and examine interstellar dust and gases out of which stars are born.", "opta": "perception", "optb": "discovery", "optc": "enquiry", "optd": "quest", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "She ...... Rs 80 out of the bank every Friday.", "opta": "obtains", "optb": "draws", "optc": "pulls", "optd": "extracts", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The American ...... presented his credentials to the President of India.", "opta": "adviser", "optb": "ambassador", "optc": "delegate", "optd": "representative", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Once he has signed the agreement, he won't be able to ......", "opta": "back up", "optb": "back in", "optc": "back at", "optd": "back out", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It was difficult to remove my feet as it had got stuck ...... in the mud.", "opta": "fairly", "optb": "greatly", "optc": "widely", "optd": "firmly", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is a very careful person, he never takes side but remains ......", "opta": "impartial", "optb": "unbiased", "optc": "neutral", "optd": "prejudiced", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "West Bengal ...... plentiful rainfall and is consequently a very green part of the country.", "opta": "misses", "optb": "receives", "optc": "expects", "optd": "regrets", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "this brand of TV is quite inferior ...... that one.", "opta": "than", "optb": "to", "optc": "with", "optd": "over", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is not what you say that ...... but what you do", "opta": "matches", "optb": "implies", "optc": "matters", "optd": "moves", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "'Please' and 'Thank you' are the little courtesies by which we keep the ...... of life oiled and running smoothly.", "opta": "path", "optb": "machine", "optc": "garden", "optd": "river", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I put ...... the light and slept.", "opta": "up", "optb": "down", "optc": "in", "optd": "out", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "...... all intents and purposes, the manager is the master of the firm.", "opta": "in", "optb": "upon", "optc": "with", "optd": "to", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The pilot had been warned about the storm, before he ......", "opta": "took away", "optb": "took up", "optc": "took over", "optd": "took off", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hardly had he arrived ...... it started raining.", "opta": "before", "optb": "when", "optc": "than", "optd": "after", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I ...... a car to be absolutely necessary these days.", "opta": "consider", "optb": "regard", "optc": "think", "optd": "agree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Besides other provisions, that shopkeeper deals ...... cosmetics.", "opta": "with", "optb": "in", "optc": "at", "optd": "for", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Leave a two inch ...... on each page for the teacher's remarks.", "opta": "border", "optb": "margin", "optc": "blank", "optd": "gap", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The team was well trained and strong, but somehow their ...... was low.", "opta": "feeling", "optb": "moral", "optc": "consciousness", "optd": "morale", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lovers were meeting each other secretly, but their ...... affair was soon known to everyone.", "opta": "clandestine", "optb": "covert", "optc": "unknown", "optd": "candid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The king ...... the rebel.", "opta": "excused", "optb": "forgave", "optc": "pardoned", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I shall call ...... you tomorrow.", "opta": "at", "optb": "on", "optc": "with", "optd": "by", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "She ...... from the crowd because of her height and flaming red hair.", "opta": "stood out", "optb": "stood off", "optc": "stood up", "optd": "stood by", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a large cities people are cut ...... from nature.", "opta": "away", "optb": "off", "optc": "out", "optd": "down", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The more your action and thought are allied and ...... the happier you grow.", "opta": "diverget", "optb": "unravelled", "optc": "integrated", "optd": "invincible", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We had a ...... of warm weather in February.", "opta": "time", "optb": "spell", "optc": "length", "optd": "phase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Physically we are now all neighbors, but psychologically. we are ...... to each other.", "opta": "primitives", "optb": "complimentary", "optc": "strangers", "optd": "cowards", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When their examinations are over, the children gleefully ...... the books they had been reading.", "opta": "shelve", "optb": "sidetrack", "optc": "overthrew", "optd": "abandon", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chintu is ...... small to start playing cricket now.", "opta": "very", "optb": "much", "optc": "too", "optd": "more", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thief ...... all the money.", "opta": "made up", "optb": "made off with", "optc": "mode do with", "optd": "made good", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The luggage was ...... heavy for him to lift", "opta": "much", "optb": "as", "optc": "so", "optd": "too", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Walking at 3'o clock, I heard the ...... of thunder.", "opta": "crackle", "optb": "rumble", "optc": "ripple", "optd": "clank", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A stone that goes on rolling ...... no moss.", "opta": "collects", "optb": "gets", "optc": "gathers", "optd": "accumulates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The earth is at present in great danger of becoming uninhabitable because of ...... environmental pollution which is going on at an incredible rapid pace.", "opta": "gigantic", "optb": "inhuman", "optc": "stupendous", "optd": "colossal", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Moreover, a fact finding mission ...... by BSN to India in January this year strongly recommended that the French group should go it alone, and not hand over ...... to an Indian Partner.", "opta": "organised, papers", "optb": "constituted, authority", "optc": "sponsored, power", "optd": "dispatched, control", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "There is a keen ...... in each trade.", "opta": "contest", "optb": "comparison", "optc": "competition", "optd": "cooperation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Now, the management graduate can expect to have a prosperous life on a ...... income without having to depend on finding a place in family busiess having to tend the paternal estates.", "opta": "professional", "optb": "regular", "optc": "meaningful", "optd": "dependable", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The boy fell ...... bicycle.", "opta": "of", "optb": "off", "optc": "from", "optd": "under", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The French ...... reputed to have a very good sense of humour.", "opta": "is", "optb": "was", "optc": "are", "optd": "will be", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Johny, where are you? ...... up this tree.", "opta": "There I am", "optb": "There am I", "optc": "Here am I", "optd": "Here I am", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "That the poor in our country, are happy is", "opta": "a dream", "optb": "a vision", "optc": "an ideal", "optd": "an illusion", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The robbers were arrested and ...... prison yesterday.", "opta": "brought into", "optb": "brought to", "optc": "taken into", "optd": "taken to", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cinema ...... a welcome escape from cramped and dull city life and the Indians are avid movie-goers.", "opta": "depicts", "optb": "highlights", "optc": "follows", "optd": "offers", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I shall take revenge ...... you.", "opta": "from", "optb": "with", "optc": "on", "optd": "at", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This book is a useful ...... to our library.", "opta": "discovery", "optb": "asset", "optc": "addition", "optd": "arrival", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The boy was cured ...... typhoid.", "opta": "from", "optb": "of", "optc": "for", "optd": "through", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The communalist represents the ...... of everything noble that we have inherited from our culture and history.", "opta": "antithesis", "optb": "antidote", "optc": "immorality", "optd": "antagonism", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is so ...... to light that he never leaves the house without sunglasses.", "opta": "insensitive", "optb": "sensitive", "optc": "afraid", "optd": "immune", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ...... of the Minister's statement cannot be verified by people who have no access to official records.", "opta": "veracity", "optb": "verbosity", "optc": "ambiguity", "optd": "validity", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "But the introductory fee does not stop after the initial handshake, brokers have to ...... it up after each transaction.", "opta": "bring", "optb": "cough", "optc": "boost", "optd": "give", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Colgate has also set an ambitious aim of ......on 8% value shared of tooth paste market by then end of first years.", "opta": "cornering", "optb": "soliciting", "optc": "disturbing", "optd": "keeping", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "...... a failure of some traffic lights, traffic is moving very slowly.", "opta": "Owing", "optb": "Due to", "optc": "Because", "optd": "Since", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The battalion operating from the mountain was able to ...... three enemy divisons.", "opta": "tie up", "optb": "tie down", "optc": "tie on", "optd": "tie with", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I purposely ...... meet you during my last visit to Kashmir.", "opta": "didn't", "optb": "won't", "optc": "hadn't", "optd": "wouldn't", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I have read one novel by Premchand. I want to read ...... novel by him.", "opta": "other", "optb": "another", "optc": "all", "optd": "few", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A man remains narrow minded, self compliance and ignorant unless he visits other people and ...... from them.", "opta": "earns", "optb": "borrows", "optc": "learns", "optd": "hears", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "My father ...... down for a nap.", "opta": "lays", "optb": "laid", "optc": "lain", "optd": "lie", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I think they allow their children too much ......", "opta": "liberality", "optb": "latitude", "optc": "lassitude", "optd": "levity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Once you suspect a person of double dealing, you ought to keep him at arm's ......", "opta": "distance", "optb": "length", "optc": "aim", "optd": "width", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Affix a revenue stamp and put your signature ...... it.", "opta": "on", "optb": "upo", "optc": "above", "optd": "over", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "My first lesson ...... forgiveness came from my mother.", "opta": "upon", "optb": "about", "optc": "in", "optd": "on", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At one point, it looked as if an area of agreement would ...... specially over the issue of productivity linked wages.", "opta": "develop", "optb": "come out", "optc": "emerge", "optd": "grow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Do you know ......?", "opta": "where she comes from", "optb": "where does she come from", "optc": "where from she comes", "optd": "from where does she come", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "God is ......", "opta": "graceful", "optb": "gracious", "optc": "grateful", "optd": "greatful", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is so ...... that he immediately believe my story of ghosts.", "opta": "innocent", "optb": "credulous", "optc": "vociferous", "optd": "credible", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}